Paola Vázquez

Mexico City | paovacs@gmail.com | +525564142809 | linkedin.com/in/paovarizo | github.com/paovarizo

Profile

I'm a Frontend Developer with 6 years of experience, specializing in React with TypeScript and JavaScript. In recent years, I have focused on working with design systems, design tokens, and creating custom components. Additionally, I have solid experience in developing web applications for various projects. I'm also actively involved in giving talks to introduce women to the tech industry.

Experience

FrontEnd Developer Ssr, Globant | Client: Autodesk

Jan 2022 - Present

- Creation of components for a design system using React, Typescript, Jest, Storybook and design tokens.
- Collaboration with the UX team on the design of the components. Figma is used for the prototyping of the components and work together for the development of the component.
- Creation of components for a MUI based design system and also customization of styles to customer requirements. Using styles as typescript objects and consuming design tokens.
- Active collaboration creating the design tokens proejct . And giving maintenance and adding new features. Technical support has also been provided to other teams within the company so that they can consume and/or collaborate on this project.
- Active help solving critical bugs and technical doubts of other teams when trying to integrate the design system to their projects.
- I have accepted the challenge of leading technical sessions with the entire team of developers to help solve their stoppers.

FrontEnd Developer, Freelance

May 2021 - Dec 2024

- Project for Motorola Mexico: A web app was made for the launch of one of their cell phones. Sockets were used to broadcast the event live in different countries and the whole web app is in react. Custom components were created to meet the client's expectations.
- Project for Nespresso: We made a web app using only HTML, CSS and JavaScript to integrate a dynamic in their products. This web app integrated a trivia where the user could win tickets for the Formula 1 in Mexico.
- Camsal Project: We performed the layout and creation of custom components to integrate a hospitality oriented website to an API called Amenitiz.

FrontEnd Developer, CuraDeuda

Nov 2020 - Jan 2022

- Implement the user interface of the entire service contracting platform. Using React, Redux and NextJs
- Creation of internal messaging platform with sockets and React
- Maintain the above mentioned platforms and also create and maintain new landing pages.
- Visual proposal of some modules using figma

Education

National Autonomous University of Mexico, BS in Computer Science

Aug 2016 - July 2021

Technologies

Languages: React, TypeScript, JavaScript, CSS and HTML

Tools and agile methods: Figma, AdobeXD and Jira

State managment: Redux and Context API

Languages

English: Level C1